# 我的天这担担面有食欲啊
My god. This dish is so appetizing
# 还真挺地道的
It's indeed authentic
# 这个担担面 我可以这么说
The Dan Dan Noodles here... I would rather say
# 比他们做的简单多了
... is much simpler than how they cook it
# 但是比那还要好
But is even better
# 担担面
Dan Dan Noodles
# 一定要买正宗的四川宜宾芽菜
You must buy authentic 'Ya Cai' (Sichuan preserved mustard greens) from Yibin, Sichuan
# 把这咸味洗洗 老的传统做法
Wash away the salty taste. This is the traditional way
# 洗干净就行了
Wash it clean would be fine
# 但是这味儿又不能完全洗掉了
You shouldn't remove the taste entirely
# 把水挤净了
Squeeze out the water
# 为了让它更香点 制点葱油
To make it more aromatic, prepare some scallion oil
# 好的花生油 差不多够了吧
High-quality peanut oil. Almost enough
# 你看大料 小茴香 桂皮 砂仁 豆蔻
See? Star anise, fennel seeds, cinnamon, amomum, and cardamom
# 洗一下它不容易糊
Wash them so they don't get burnt easily
# 把它洗干净了 慢慢沁炸 油不要太热
Wash it clean. Soak-fry it slowly. The oil shouldn't be too hot
# 顺便搁点葱 有香味
Add some scallion as well. It's aromatic
# 要切点姜 拍一下
Cut some ginger. Smash it
# 还得来点这个 葱绿
We also need some of this. Scallion leaves
# 这就慢慢的沁炸 没什么可复杂的
Simply soak-fry it. Nothing complicated
# 辣椒面我们可以搁点香油
Add some seasome oil in the chili pepper powder
# 它出来更有香味
so that it smells more aromatic
# 咱们拌一拌 不容易一下就糊了
Mix it up so that it doesn't get burnt immediately
# 以前都是拌水啊师父
We used to mix it with water, master
# 对拌水也可以  今天又学一招
- Yeah, mixing with water is also ok. - That's another new trick today
# 过去讲二合油炒菜香啊
We used to say that the mixed oil gives great aroma for a dish
# 搁点猪油 你闻这气味
Add some pork lard. Smell it
# 这个担担面 你看简单
This recipe of Dan Dan Noodles... You see, it's simple
# 它跟别人做法不一样
But different from how other people cooks it
# 这是力力餐厅的一道名菜
It's a famous dish of Li Li Restaurant
# 我们上学的时候都在那实习
When we were studying cooking, we did our internship there
# 然后当时那师傅很厉害
At that time, the master chef was awesome
# 有一个面点师傅叫都国良
There was a pastry chef named Du Guoliang
# 那在四川是非常有名望的
He was very famous and prestigious in Sichuan
# 这是传承他的担担面
This recipe is inherited from him
# 非常简单 而且你看还好吃
Very simple. And delicious
# 咱给它捞出来
Let's haul it out
# 这就行了 温度行了
This is ok. At the right temperature
# 一下（下多了）就糊了 这可以慢慢加
Add the oil one-off, it'll be burnt. We can do it slowly
# 这样油热点 它糊不了
So that it doesn't get burnt even if the oil is too hot
# 一次次加热
Heat it several times
# 你看我为什么这么试呢
Why am I doing this?
# 就让网友学这个他有把握
Because I want our audiences to learn the details well
# 油耗完了 现在调汁 我煮面
I've used up the oil. Now prepare the sauce and boil some noodles
# 这个东西很简单
This is really simple
# 小葱花 不能切成葱末
Cut the scallion in this way. Don't mince it
# 这个芽菜可以搁点 让它香
Add some 'Ya Cai' (Sichuan preserved mustard green) to make it aromatic
# 味精其实对人体没有害 沏出来没问题
MSG is acutally not harmful to our health, at least in this way
# 因为这个温度不够 它到不了八十五度
Since the temperature is not high enough. It hasn't reached 85 degrees Celcius
# 可以搁点猪油 提提香
We can add some lard to enhance the aroma
# 要没有也没关系
It's ok if you don't have it
# 这一碗酱油
And the soy sauce here
# 然后还有一样重要的东西 这个师父
One other important thing. This one, master
# 灵魂 灵魂就是红油
The soul. The red chili oil is the soul
# 安逸 巴适得很
Nice. This is really amazing
# 说话有水平啊
That's the right way to say it
# 要的 煮面喽
Okay! Boil the noodles
# 这个就是普通的切面 细切面
These are just normal noodles. Thin cut noodles
# 过去是用好鸡汤
In the past we used decent chicken broth
# 我们今天不用鸡汤
Today we don't use chicken broth
# 我们就用这原汤 也一样
Use the noodle water here. It's equivalent
# 也还原这味道
It can also reproduce the best taste
# 简单当中它不是我的味道不好
In short, it's not that it tastes bad
# 如果说你要炒了
Instead, if you stir-fry it
# 这芽菜的味道就会失去了很多
Most of the flavor in 'Ya Cai' will be gone
# 炒完了这个味道马上就变了
It tastes different immediately after frying
# 就不好吃了
and it goes bad
# 这个担担面 我可以这么说
This recipe of Dan Dan Noodles, I would say
# 比他们做的简单多了
is much simpler than how other people cook it
# 但是比那还要好吃
But tastes even better
# 这个技艺几乎没了 我今天还原给你们
This recipe is almost lost. I reproduce it for you here now
# 熟了 再烫个油菜心
It's done. Boil some choy sum
# 还有一个什么呢
What else?
# 冲一下汤 为什么得先冲汤
Add the hot noodle water into the bowl. Why do this first?
# 必须开锅冲这汤
We must use the hot noodle water to make the 'soup'
# 如果你要后加 把面条搁上再冲汤
If you are doing it later, say put the noodles on the sauce and add water later
# 这香气就出不来
The aroma is not going out
# 你看它这东西就这么怪
It is indeed interesting
# 太有食欲了
So appetizing
# 我的天呐这担担面有食欲啊
My god. The Dan Dan Noodles are so appetizing
# 既简单又好吃 家里又能操作的
Simple and delicious. You can easily do this at home
# 来点汤
Add some soup
# 这怎么样 够不够小魏 咸味
What do you think? Is it salty enough, Wei?
# 芽菜的香味儿 辣味
The aroma of 'Ya Cai', the spicy flavor
# 包括红油跟面的这种碰撞
And the collision between the red chili oil and noodles
# 这一站就到四川啦 巴适得很
I feel I'm already in Sichuan. Tastes amazing
# 你吃一口尝尝
Take a bite
# 你干了二十年老面点师了
You've been a pastry chef for 20 years
# 师父也不是干面点的
I am not a pastry chef myself
# 再喝口汤
Try the soup?
# 这真挺地道的 真挺好吃的
This is so authentic. Delicious indeed
# 它吃完了没有麻酱糊嘴的味儿
You don't have the 'sticky' feeling of seasame sauce after eating
# 这个汤就得烫点 越烫越好
The soup should be hot. The hotter, the better
# 再来点 多吃点儿
Have some more!
# 以下字幕暂时没有时间轴，请直接审核文字
# 有网友问 说家里的火没有饭店里那么旺
# Some fans say that the cooking stoves in their homes are not as powerful as those in restaurants
# 所以在家炒菜的时候怎么能够控制火候
# and they wonder how to control the temperature when cooking at home
# 有什么技巧
# and if there are some tricks
# 在家里边 火比较弱
# Generally the heaters in home are not powerful enough
# 尽量让它温度稍微高一点
# So you should try to use a slightly higher temperature
# 然后这量呢
# and the amount of food...
# 你如果说在家里边炒菜量要太大
# If you are cooking a lot of food for one dish in your home
# 也不行
# that's not gonna work
# 根本不行
# not at all
# 这量适当的合适
# The amount of food should be moderate
# 你要说够一盘吃的
# Say, if the amount is about one plate
# 那基本就没问题
# Basically it'll be fine
# 所以在炒的这过程当中
# During the cooking process
# 一是我们把油温升高 把锅温升高
# Firstly, enhance the temperatures of the oil and the wok
# 炒菜当中要采取其它一些措施
# Some other measures should be taken while cooking
# 如果说要炒菜 还有一个方法
# If you are stir-frying, there is another trick
# 要把它分类炒开了
# Stir-fry each ingredient separately
# 能用碗汁的 我们兑个碗汁
# For example, if 'bowl-sauce' (prepare all condiments in one bowl in advance) is applicable, you can make one
# 比如说荤料的东西我们先滑了
# Slightly fry the meat before cooking
# 滑好以后捞出来
# Fish the meat out of the oil
# 刷完锅我们再升温炒一些配料
# Rinse the wok, raise the temperature and stir-fry some other ingredients
# 这样把它分段给解开了
# In this way, the dish is separated into several 'sections'
# 分解开了再一块投进去
# Finally, mix every ingredient together in the wok
# 你这样下碗汁之后先别急着扒拉
# Add the 'bowl-sauce', but don't stir the food immediately
# 让它凝固一下
# Let it condense for a while
# 你这样再翻
# And then you can toss the wok
# 相对来讲就解决了这个问题
# Such that this problem can be fixed
# 火的问题就解决了
# the temperature loss problem due to low power heater
# 明白了吧
# You get it?